<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on ivychapel.ink</title>
    <link>https://ivychapel.ink/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on ivychapel.ink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ivychapel.ink/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On avoiding band-aid security</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-avoiding-band-aid-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-avoiding-band-aid-security/</guid>
      <description>Applying band-aid to open wounds is an important step in preventing further infection, yet it rarely addresses the underlying issue.
Some of my work duties as an executive in a security products companyis helping key customers better understand the security challenges they’re going through, and shape the vision for future improvements.
The other day I was talking to a customer, and a familiar narrative surfaced:
 “We’ve had a pentest from company X, we’ve covered 100% of detected weaknesses, devised long-term security improvement program based on their recommendations, yet, a year after that, we’ve had 2 incidents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On keeping secrets in comfort</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-keeping-secrets-in-comfort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-keeping-secrets-in-comfort/</guid>
      <description>As someone who used to spend a lot of time analyzing how security incidents happen, I frequently think how little, unfortunately, technical peculiarities have to do with most security breaches.
 Making people keep secrets is very hard. Making groups follow guidelines is laborious. Making secrecy policies work in groups is even harder.
You can fail only once .
 To prevent OPSEC failures, we’re constructing hi-tech clutches to human problems, frequently without trying to understand the nature of the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>