<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on ivychapel.ink</title>
    <link>https://ivychapel.ink/tags/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on ivychapel.ink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ivychapel.ink/tags/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Guessing Apple&#39;s CSAM motivations</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/guessing-apple-csam-motivations/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/guessing-apple-csam-motivations/</guid>
      <description>With all gloom&amp;rsquo;n&amp;rsquo;doom scenarios about CSAM misuse have been pointed out and outrage about change in value proposition is heating up, I am missing one interesting angle in the Apple CSAM discussion:
 Implementation of any security control/technology is an exercise in security budget allocation. What is the expected change in security posture/risk resistance and how much it will cost? Are there more important risks we can address with equal budget?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generic questions breed generic answers</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/generic-questions-breed-generic-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/generic-questions-breed-generic-answers/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Should I use TLS for HIPAA compliance?” “Is self-signed certificate OK for mutual TLS authentication?” “Can I work without a security policy but with awesome security engineers?” “Can I have PEP and PDP in the same component of my application?”  Mmm, maybe… Hell yeah! Sure you can! Oh, no! Avoid at all costs!
I’m tired, can I go now?
Without a certain level of precision and context in communication, there are very few mutually understandable reference points between people who build and people who protect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less obvious parts of security asymmetries</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/less-obvious-asymmetries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/less-obvious-asymmetries/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve been around infosec industry for a while, you might be familiar with an old adage:
 defender has to get most (if not all) things right to meet his goals, while attacker has to get a few things right and he wins.
 This is unfair, but the closer you look, the more asymmetries unfold: for example, what exactly does “get things right” mean? It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting mental exercise, so let’s do it together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On avoiding band-aid security</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-avoiding-band-aid-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-avoiding-band-aid-security/</guid>
      <description>Applying band-aid to open wounds is an important step in preventing further infection, yet it rarely addresses the underlying issue.
Some of my work duties as an executive in a security products companyis helping key customers better understand the security challenges they’re going through, and shape the vision for future improvements.
The other day I was talking to a customer, and a familiar narrative surfaced:
 “We’ve had a pentest from company X, we’ve covered 100% of detected weaknesses, devised long-term security improvement program based on their recommendations, yet, a year after that, we’ve had 2 incidents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On keeping secrets in comfort</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-keeping-secrets-in-comfort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-keeping-secrets-in-comfort/</guid>
      <description>As someone who used to spend a lot of time analyzing how security incidents happen, I frequently think how little, unfortunately, technical peculiarities have to do with most security breaches.
 Making people keep secrets is very hard. Making groups follow guidelines is laborious. Making secrecy policies work in groups is even harder.
You can fail only once .
 To prevent OPSEC failures, we’re constructing hi-tech clutches to human problems, frequently without trying to understand the nature of the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>