<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ivychapel.ink</title>
    <link>https://ivychapel.ink/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ivychapel.ink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ivychapel.ink/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On avoiding band-aid security</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-avoiding-band-aid-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-avoiding-band-aid-security/</guid>
      <description>Applying band-aid to open wounds is an important step in preventing further injury, yet it rarely addresses the illness.
Some of my work duties as an executive in security products company is helping key customers better understand the security challenges they’re going through, and shape the vision for future improvements.
The other day I was talking to a customer, and a familiar narrative surfaced:
 “We’ve had a pentest from X, we’ve covered 100% of detected weaknesses, devised long-term security improvement program based on their recommendations, yet, a year after that, we’ve had 2 incidents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubler-Ross model for engineers turning into managers</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/kubler-ross-model-for-engineers-turning-into-managers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/kubler-ross-model-for-engineers-turning-into-managers/</guid>
      <description>Having quickly jumped position ladders in the past, I always had that scary stare in the mirror: “I am not supposed to build new great stuff with my hands anymore”. In my own life, I was lucky to be facing the need to build companies — which is even more challenging. But for many, life turns into endless position hopping in the Dilbert comic.
Many of my peers struggle to the very day, so here you go:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two types of engineering for resiliency</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/two-types-of-engineering-for-resiliency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/two-types-of-engineering-for-resiliency/</guid>
      <description>As you might&amp;rsquo;ve noticed already, I spend quite a lot of time thinking about the way we think when we choose this or that way to solve problems and engineer things against risk. Another brief note on the subject, picking up metaphors from some twitter discussion I&amp;rsquo;ve loved.
There are two metaphors for resiliency and risk management in traditional engineering — the NASA way and the US Navy way. I’m not entirely sure how they reflect reality, given the story of Apollo Guidance Computer’s design, but they’re very valid to make the point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why decentralized social services fail (so far)</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/why-decentralized-social-services-fail-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/why-decentralized-social-services-fail-so-far/</guid>
      <description>Once in a while I read about another decentralized social network, all filled with great ideas, strong privacy features, interesting cryptographic defenses against data misuse and a mission to finally disrupt everything social as we know it. Seeing new ones come and go, there are plenty of ways in which they fail, but the discussion around them almost always misses the reason “why”, focusing on “how” instead (which is merely stating the obvious).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SkyNet will not destroy humanity; poor code might</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/skynet-vs-poor-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/skynet-vs-poor-code/</guid>
      <description>NOTE (August 2019) : it takes only a few years for some of the obvious things you see to become reality. Feeling a prophet of “Told you so” preaching is not rewarding, it feels all bad that these prophecies come true
 Lately, with increasing frequency, I became subject to real-world effects of bad software (yes, that one which is eating the world, supposedly).
A flight could not depart for 70 minutes, because remote airport wouldn’t register arriving passenger’s documents, due to ‘some security certificate problem’ (someone forgot to update pinned certificate?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On keeping secrets in comfort</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-keeping-secrets-in-comfort/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-keeping-secrets-in-comfort/</guid>
      <description>As someone who used to spend a lot of time analyzing how security incidents happen, I frequently think how little, unfortunately, technical peculiarities have to do with most security breaches.
 Making people keep secrets is very hard. Making groups follow guidelines is laborious. Making secrecy policies work in groups is even harder.
You can fail only once .
 To prevent OPSEC failures, we’re constructing hi-tech clutches to human problems, frequently without trying to understand the nature of the problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>