<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>engineering on ivychapel.ink</title>
    <link>https://ivychapel.ink/tags/engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in engineering on ivychapel.ink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ivychapel.ink/tags/engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Two types of engineering for resiliency</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/two-types-of-engineering-for-resiliency/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/two-types-of-engineering-for-resiliency/</guid>
      <description>I spend quite a lot of time thinking about the way we think.
In particular, I think a lot about the way we make engineering choices that mitigate risks. So, this is another brief note on the subject, following the beautiful metaphor I overheard:
 There are two metaphors for resiliency and risk management in traditional engineering — the NASA way and the US Navy way.
  NASA way is about provably correct systems, consistent engineering, repeatable practices and forbidding certain system behaviors that impose great risk, or working around it with systematic redundancy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why decentralized social services fail (so far)</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/why-decentralized-social-services-fail-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/why-decentralized-social-services-fail-so-far/</guid>
      <description>Once in a while I read about another decentralized social network, full of great social ideas, strong privacy features, interesting cryptographic defenses against data misuse. The new underdog is typically on a mission to finally disrupt &amp;ldquo;centralized&amp;rdquo; social media platform as we know it, but in a nice fair way. Then it goes away into oblivion again.
Discussion around how these decentralized platforms fail almost always misses the reason “why”, focusing on the technical “how” instead.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>