<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>musings on ivychapel.ink</title>
    <link>https://ivychapel.ink/tags/musings/</link>
    <description>Recent content in musings on ivychapel.ink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ivychapel.ink/tags/musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On shortness of time</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/on-time/</guid>
      <description>Over the last decade I went through a set of slow “getting-used-to-this-thought” realisations about time. They have transformed the way I work and what I work on. Many humans have walked this track of thought, many of their words echo in mine, so I&amp;rsquo;ll add mine to this infinite pool. Being obvious, they matter to me more than many eureka moments and epiphanies.
When I was younger, time was abundant, and I learnt to play as if time didn’t exist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Less obvious parts of security asymmetries</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/less-obvious-asymmetries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/less-obvious-asymmetries/</guid>
      <description>If you’ve been around infosec industry for a while, you might be familiar with an old adage:
 defender has to get most (if not all) things right to meet his goals, while attacker has to get a few things right and he wins.
 This is unfair, but the closer you look, the more asymmetries unfold: for example, what exactly does “get things right” mean? It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting mental exercise, so let’s do it together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why decentralized social services fail (so far)</title>
      <link>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/why-decentralized-social-services-fail-so-far/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ivychapel.ink/posts/why-decentralized-social-services-fail-so-far/</guid>
      <description>Once in a while I read about another decentralized social network, full of great social ideas, strong privacy features, interesting cryptographic defenses against data misuse. The new underdog is typically on a mission to finally disrupt &amp;ldquo;centralized&amp;rdquo; social media platform as we know it, but in a nice fair way. Then it goes away into oblivion again.
Discussion around how these decentralized platforms fail almost always misses the reason “why”, focusing on the technical “how” instead.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>