<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lojong</title>
    <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lojong</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Copyright notice</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 21:37:58 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://ivychapel.ink/l/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 21:37:58 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/about/</guid>
      <description>This is some static page where you can write about yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A summary of the essential instructions: Train in the five forces</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/17/</guid>
      <description>The five forces summarize the crucial points of practice and, in a single phrase, contain numerous profound key instructions for the practice of the holy dharma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All Dharma agrees at one point</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/19/</guid>
      <description>Since the purpose of all dharma, both mahayana and hinayana, is simply to tame ego-clinging, as you practice dharma or work at mind training, ego-clinging should decrease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All active meditation is done in one way.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/39/</guid>
      <description>Continue practice into everyday life with a single meditation, always keeping in mind the intention to help others in all activities, eating, dressing, sleeping, walking, or sitting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All corrections are made in one way.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/40/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/40/</guid>
      <description>Analysis itself is used to correct mistakes in analysis. If, when you are meditating on mind training, adverse conditions develop, people criticize and insult you, demons, devils, enemies, and disputes trouble you, your disturbing emotions become stronger, or you have no desire to meditate, think:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Always have the support of a joyful mind.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/21/</guid>
      <description>When there is never any fear or despair no matter what adversity or suffering is encountered, when difficulty is taken as an aid to mind training and you always have the help of a joyful mind, then you have acquired proficiency in mind training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Always meditate on volatile points.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/49/</guid>
      <description>Meditate by skillfully bringing out extra love and compassion for subjects that present difficulties in mind training: aggressive enemies, troublesome obstacles, particularly those who act perversely and respond to your help by making trouble, people who compete with you, casual friends, people who are troublesome even though there is no bad feeling, or those with whom you just don&amp;rsquo;t get along.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Always practice the three great principles.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/23/</guid>
      <description>Of the three general principles, the first is not to break the promises you have made in mind training, that is, not to be tarnished by any fault or failing in any vow you have taken, including even the most minor precepts of individual liberation, bodhisattva, or vajrayana ordinations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>At the beginning and at the end, two things to be done.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/41/</guid>
      <description>At the beginning, as soon as you wake up 1n the morning, generate very strongly the impetus:
 Today, I shall keep the two bodhicittas with me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be grateful to everyone</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/13/</guid>
      <description>Work on taking and sending with these considerations in mind:
 In general, all methods for attaining buddhahood rely on sentient beings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Begin the sequence of exchange with yourself</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/10/</guid>
      <description>In order to be able to take on the sufferings of others, begin the sequence of exchange with yourself. Right now, take on mentally all the suffering that will ripen for you in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change your attitude, but remain neutral.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/24/</guid>
      <description>To change and reverse your previous attitude of concern with your own welfare and lack of concern for the welfare of others, take only the welfare of others as being important.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do not allow three things to weaken.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/46/</guid>
      <description>Learn not to let these three things weaken:
 Faith and respect for your guru must not weaken since all the fine qualities of mahayana dharma depend on him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t aim to win.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/35/</guid>
      <description>In a horse race, the aim is to be the fastest. Among dharma people there are often hopes of receiving more attention or being more highly regarded than others, and little schemes are made up to find ways to acquire possessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t be caught up in irritation.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/57/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/57/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t take a jealous attitude toward others. When others disparage you in public or cause trouble for you, don&amp;rsquo;t react or let your mind and feelings be disturbed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t be excited by cutting remarks.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/31/</guid>
      <description>In general, don&amp;rsquo;t take joy in disparaging others. In particular, when another person says something bad about you, don&amp;rsquo;t respond by talking maliciously about him to others.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t be temperamental.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/58/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/58/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t trouble the minds of your companions by showing your pleasure or displeasure on every little matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t depend on external conditions.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/50/</guid>
      <description>Have no regard for conducive or adverse conditions, strong or weak health, wealth or poverty, good or bad reputation, troubles or absence of troubles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t expect thanks.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/59/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/59/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t hope that others will express their gratitude in words of thanks for your own practice of dharma, your helping others, or your practicing virtue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t fluctuate.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/53/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/53/</guid>
      <description>A person who sometimes practices and sometimes doesn&amp;rsquo;t has not developed a definite understanding of dharma. Don&amp;rsquo;t have a lot of projects on your mind, but do mind training single-mindedly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t make a fuss.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/56/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/56/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t make a big fuss even when you are kind to another person, because you are, in fact, just working at regarding others as more important than yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t make mistakes.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/52/</guid>
      <description>Avoid six mistakes.
 To endure patiently the suffering of subduing enemies, protecting friends, and working to make money and not to endure patiently the difficulties of dharma practice is mistaken patience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t make things painful.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/33/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t speak in a way that causes pain for others, either by making pointed remarks and exposing their faults or, in the case of nonhuman beings, by using mantras that drain their life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t put the horse&#39;s load on a pony.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/34/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/34/</guid>
      <description>To give someone else an unpleasant job that is your responsibility or, by resorting to trickery, to shift a problem you have encountered to someone else is like putting a horse&amp;rsquo;s load on a pony.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t reduce a god to demon.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/37/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/37/</guid>
      <description>If, as you meditate on mind training, your personality becomes stiff with pride and arrogance, it&amp;rsquo;s as though you have reduced a god to a demon; dharma has become nondharma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t rely on consistency.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/30/</guid>
      <description>A person who is consistent in his affairs doesn&amp;rsquo;t forget the people who concern him, no matter where he is or how much time has gone by.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t revert to magic.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/36/</guid>
      <description>If you accept a setback for the time being out of a desire for future benefits for yourself or if you practice mind training expecting to cure illness and mental disturbances and ward off adverse situations, your practice is mistaken, like someone contriving magical rituals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t seek pain as source of happiness.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/38/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t think: &amp;ldquo;If that patron or person should become ill or die, I would receive a lot of food and money&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;If this fellow monk or these dharma companions were to die, I would obtain their images and books&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;If my colleagues were to die, all the merit would come to me alone&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Wouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be wonderful if all my enemies were to die!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t talk about weak points.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/25/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t discuss unpleasant subjects: other people&amp;rsquo;s faults in wordly matters (such as physical or mental disabilities) or their faults in spiritual matters (violations of ordination, for instance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t think about the affairs of others.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/26/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/26/</guid>
      <description>Do not think about other people&amp;rsquo;s affairs: in general, the faults of any sentient being, but in particular, the faults of anyone who has entered the practice of dharma.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t wait in an ambush.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/32/</guid>
      <description>When someone has caused you trouble, the tendency is to fix it in mind and never forget it though many years go by.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drive all blame into one</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/12/</guid>
      <description>Relative Bodhicitta For the first way:
 Drive all blame into one
 Whether you are physically ill, troubled in your mind, insulted by others, or bothered by enemies and disputes, in short, whatever annoyance, major or minor, comes up in your life or affairs, do not lay the blame on anything else, thinking that such-and-such caused this or that problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Even the remedy is freed to subside naturally.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/4/</guid>
      <description>When you look at the presence of the remedy itself, these thoughts about the absence of true existence, there is nothing for mind to refer to and they subside naturally on their own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Examine the nature of unborn awareness.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/3/</guid>
      <description>When you look directly at the presence of mind, no color, no shape, no form is perceived. Since mind has no origin, it has never come into existence in the first place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Find freedom through both examination and investigation.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/55/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/55/</guid>
      <description>You must find freedom from disturbing emotions and ego-clinging by constantly examining and investigating your course of experience. Therefore, turn your attention to an object that gives rise to disturbing emotions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First, train in preliminaries</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/00000/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/00000/</guid>
      <description>Preliminaries to a Period of Meditation First, at the beginning of every period of meditation, imagine your root guru sitting on a lotus-and-moon seat above your head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First, train in preliminaries</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/1/</guid>
      <description>Preliminaries to a Period of Meditation First, at the beginning of every period of meditation, imagine your root guru sitting on a lotus-and-moon seat above your head.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give up all hope for result.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/28/</guid>
      <description>Give up the hope of subduing gods and demons by meditating on mind training, or the hope that you will be considered a good person when you try to help someone who has hurt you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Give up poisonous food.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/29/</guid>
      <description>Since all virtuous thoughts and actions motivated by clinging to a concrete reality or to a self-cherishing attitude are like poisonous food, give them up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In order to take unexpected conditions as the path, immediately join whatever you meet with meditation.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/16/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/16/</guid>
      <description>When illness, demons, interruptions, or disturbing emotions come unexpectedly, or if you see someone else troubled by some unpleasant situation, think, &amp;ldquo;I shall just practice taking and sending.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In postmeditation practice, be a child of illusion.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/6/</guid>
      <description>After meditation, do not allow the experience of resting evenly to dissipate, no matter what form of activity you engage in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learn the three difficult points.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/44/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/44/</guid>
      <description>At first, it is difficult to recognize disturbing emotions. Then, it is difficult to overcome them. In the end, it is difficult to cut their continuity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make the three inseparable.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/47/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/47/</guid>
      <description>Make the three faculties-body, speech, and mind - always inseparable from virtuous actions, and refrain from evil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observe the two, even at risk of your life.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/43/</guid>
      <description>Since all present and future happiness comes from carefully observing the general precepts of dharma contained in the three ordinations and the particular precepts of mind training with their corresponding commitments, observe both these sets of precepts even at the risk of your life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of the two judges, hold the principal one</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/20/</guid>
      <description>For other people to see you as a dharma person is one judge, but ordinary people do not know what is hidden in your mind and may just be taking joy in certain improvements in the way you act.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regard all phenomena as dreams</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/2/</guid>
      <description>Actual phenomena - that is, the world and its inhabitants - are objects that we grasp at with our senses. These appearances are simply our mind&amp;rsquo;s manifestations of confusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rest in the nature of all, the basis of everything.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/5/</guid>
      <description>This instruction presents the actual method of placing the mind. When there is no involvement with the activity of the seven groups of consciousness, there is still the nature of all phenomena, the natural state, which is the basis of everything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take up the three primary resources.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/45/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/45/</guid>
      <description>The primary resources for working at dharma are:
 a good guru, the proper practice of dharma with a workable mind, and suitable conditions for dharma practice - food, clothing, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The four applications are the best method</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/15/</guid>
      <description>The four applications are accumulating merit, con- fessing evil actions, giving torma to gods and demons, and offering torma to dakinis and protectors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This time, practice the important points.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/51/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/51/</guid>
      <description>From time without beginning, you have taken existence in innumerable forms, in all of which nothing meaningful has been done. A similar coincidence of the conducive conditions in this life will not come about in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three objects, three poisons, three seeds of virtue.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/8/</guid>
      <description>The three poisons continually arise in connection with three objects. Compulsive attachment arises for objects that are pleasant or useful; aversion arises for objects that are unpleasant or harmful; and stupidity or indifference for other objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To see confusion as the four kayas, The protection of emptiness is insurpassable</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/14/</guid>
      <description>In general all appearances, and particularly adverse conditions, are like the distress experienced when you dream of being burnt in a fire or swept away by a flood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train in all areas without bias. Overall deep and pervasive proficiency is important.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/48/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/48/</guid>
      <description>Without partiality for certain areas, mind training by itself should pervade everything, good or bad, which arises as an object of experience: other sentient beings, the four elements, or nonhuman beings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train in taking and sending alternately. Put them on the breath.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/7/</guid>
      <description>As you think:
 All these parents of mine, who are the focus of compassion, are hurt directly by suffering and indirectly by the source of suffering, so I shall take on myself all the different kinds of suffering in all my mothers&amp;rsquo; course of experience and the source of suffering, all disturbing emotions and actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Train wholeheartedly.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/54/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/54/</guid>
      <description>Without indulging any distraction, train yourself only in mind training, being completely involved with this one concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Use sayings to train in all forms of activity.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/9/</guid>
      <description>All the time, repeat these or other suitable sayings and cultivate these attitudes vigorously.
From Shantideva:
 While their evil ripens in me, May all my virtue ripen in them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do at death</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/18/</guid>
      <description>The mahayana instructions for how to die Are the five forces. How you act is important.
 When a person who has trained in this teaching is stricken by terminal illness, he or she should practice the five forces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When evil fills the world and it&#39;s inhabitants, change adverse conditions into path of awakening</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/11/</guid>
      <description>When your world is full of the pain and suffering that are the fruition of evil - when prosperity and wealth are diminishing, troublesome people create difficulties, and so on - you must change the adverse conditions in which you find yourself into the path of awakening.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whichever of two occurs, be patient.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/42/</guid>
      <description>If you become utterly destitute and are suffering greatly, consider your previous karma. Without being resentful or depressed, take up all the sufferings and evil of others and work hard at ways to clear away evil actions and obscurations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Work on the stronger disturbing emotions first.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/27/</guid>
      <description>Examine your personality to determine which disturbing emotions are strongest. Concentrate all dharma practice on them in the beginning, and subdue and clear them away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are proficient if you can practice even when distracted.</title>
      <link>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/22/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://ivychapel.ink/l/posts/22/</guid>
      <description>A skilled horseman does not fall from his horse, even when he is distracted. In the same way, if you are able to take adverse conditions that suddenly develop as aids to mind training even without expressly directing your attention to do so, then you are proficient in mind training.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>